So this is the start of a project rather ambitious idea, just an experiment, but
one that I'm pretty excited about. The idea is one that I've had for a while since
I saw this robot at my favorite local thrift store. It was in the expensive
boutique section, so I did pay like $45 for it, but I think it was worth it. Currently
I have it a little bit disassembled, but basically it's just missing an arm. Otherwise
that's more or less what it looks like. The head is currently detached and I've
done more disassembly internally, but this is basically the idea. It's circa maybe 80s or 90s
toy that, oh, actually this is missing the bottom. So this is the base, which, so you can see it moves
around and has eyes that light up. There's also lights inside of the blue lights, really good.
So, okay, so the head comes off. I've taken it off, that is. I just had to unscrew some screws,
and I also undid or rather clipped a bunch of the wires. So now it comes apart into really
three nice parts, three nice pieces. So there's this body assembly, oops, let's
select this arm in there. So, okay, more than three pieces, but we'll consider these the
three main components right now. There's the body and arm assembly, the bottom wheels and motors
moving around. And it's pretty simple here, just two motors to move these wheels independently,
and then a couple other wheels for stabilizing. And then there's the head. Looks like this. I have
taken out kind of a cool old circuit board. I might have misplaced it, but that went in the back
here. I don't intend to keep that at least not as part of this project, but I do want to keep
these three main components because I think they kind of serve as neat discrete functions of what I
want to eventually build, which is a working robot that moves around my floor and can interact
with the world around me and with people in different ways. So I want to try and build this as
quickly as I can. I've gotten pretty quick at building software these days using all the latest tools,
but this will be my first time doing actual robotics work. So I'm being fairly ambitious.
But I also think that this is a nice first project for one because I have the materials,
at least some of them. And also, as I said, it's really kind of nicely compartmentalized into
these three pieces. So I think what I'd like to do is work kind of independently on this locomotion
base. So getting something that can just kind of move around this floor. And then in here, I think I'll
put, I think this is kind of a nice compartment that I can put, you know, something's still
wonderful. I'm thinking maybe even like a oatmeal canister, but you know, one of those cardboard
ones and I just stick it in there and I could extract it to see what I then to keep in here,
which is the main computing and power supply. So all of the computational logic.
And then ultimately, and this should not be part of the first 1.0 build, but ultimately, I
really like that these sockets for the arms are really easy to imagine swapping out for other
components. So just imagine having like a vacuum cleaner or just a more capable robotic arm
that we attach to it. So that's kind of the idea for this is to have computer and
just sort of the main interface be in there. And then in the head, of course, I want to have the
input and output components. So some kind of a camera, it already has a speaker in here,
which I'd like to keep using that. So it'll have to have, you know, microphone and camera,
at least one camera. You know, I've got some kind of creative ideas for what to do with the head
as well. I'd also like to get it to move around. You know, get it to swivel. It'd be cool to get it
to be able to pivot up and down as well. But that would maybe be more mechanical engineering
than I can do right now. Also, these arms, you know, if you look at this, it's a fairly complex
assembly. It's got a few joints and different pieces. I haven't opened this up, but
well, this is on a spring. Open that like that. So, you know, you could imagine
something that can bend and unbend these arms. Currently, it's not not very well lubricated, but
I guess it's set up to be sort of set in place. So that's the main assembly. And what I have for
one more thing I'll say about the head. And this is kind of what inspired this, an idea that
I would love to do. Okay. So here's the crazy idea. I got this projector from Amazon,
and it's real cheap. It was like 40 bucks. I'm a little disappointed in how cheaply built it is,
but I guess I should have expected that. But I did try it out, and it works well enough for basically
what I might imagine putting in a robot like this. I mean, actually, you know, it fits inside
this head, too. So imagine, imagine just this yellow part flipping up and this being inside
so that you could have a video screen projected onto a wall. And so this robot could travel
around the house and could interact with you and also show you arbitrary images
that a computer could render. So that's kind of the setup. And my instructions, I think,
would be to sort of set this up as a multi-worker project. So I imagine having different sub agents
that are specialized and even sub-projects specialized to these different components.
And I'm trying to build this quickly, so I want to use everything that I have on hand.
So I think I do have a Raspberry, not a Raspberry Pi. Yes, a Raspberry Pi somewhere
that I could repurpose for this, but I was thinking I could try also to use this chrome box.
Then I got from eBay. I got a bunch of these. This would obviously not be on unbattery,
but I could just plug it in for now. You know, I want to keep the software as familiar as I can to
me. I'm pretty comfortable developing in Python and Docker. So as much as we can work with
sort of the Python, Docker, Linux, open source stack, all the better. And
yeah, I can plan to go to a first store this weekend, but really I want to get as much of this done
as possible using basically this as context. So what I've shown here, and of course I can do follow-ups
as needed, but this is the idea. I wonder what will come of it. I'm excited.
We're just shy of 10 minutes with context. Okay, I'm going to stop.